A racing second hand, a shooting comet!
عقرب دقائق مسرِع، مُذنّب ساقط
Conan's logic works great on hearts tired by modern society!
تُعالج استنتاجات كونان القلوب المُثقلة بالمجتمع الحديث
The JDL's in trouble today! Wisdom, courage, and teamwork!
!فرقة فتيان التحرّي في ورطة اليوم !الحكمة والشجاعة وعمل الفريق
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
The Junior Detective League Shipwreck Case.
قضيّة كارثة فرقة فتيان التحرّي
Sorry! You ok?! I didn't see you there!
آسف! أأنتم بخير؟ كنت شارد الذهن !ولم أنتبه لكم
Yahoo! This is great!
!مرحى! هذا رائع
It's the best summer break ever!
!إنّها أفضل عطلة صيفية
I'm glad we came to the ocean prepared!
من الجيّد أنّنا أتينا للمحيط متحضّرين
Kasuda-san? Of Kasuda Industries?
كاسودا-سان؟ من شركة صناعات كاسودا؟
Yep! I'm a rich kid who's ignorant of his debt to his old man!
أجل، أنا فتى ثريّ! شاب طائش لا يزال لا يلقي لأبيه اهتماماً
Are you sure taking us all back isn't a problem?
لكن ألم نسبب لك ضيقاً؟ فقد أخذتنا جميعاً في عودتك
The more the merrier! Right, Shinobu?
كلما زاد العدد زادت المتعة! صحيح يا شينوبو؟
Yeah!
نعم
I sure am jealous! Going scuba diving as a couple!
أغبطكما حقّاً، تغوصان بأجهزة تنفّس معاً كحبيبين
Yeah, a couple...
حبيبين؟
Well, if I wasn't rich, there's no telling how she'd have wound up...
،حسناً، لو لم أكن فتىً ثريّاً لما صاحبتني شينوبو غالباً
Teruhiko-san! That's horrible!
...تيروهيكو-سان! لستُ كذلك
It's okay to be honest, Shinobu.
لا بأس من الصراحة يا شينوبو
What's his deal?! Suddenly fighting with his girlfriend...
ما خطبه؟ يتشاجر مع حبيبته فجأةً
Hey, Ran-neechan. Where's the old man fishing anyway?
ران-نيتشان، أين يصيد العمّ؟
He said it was the best spot in the area and left before dawn...
قال أنّه يوجد موقع صيد ممتاز في هذه المنطقة وغادر قبل طلوع الشمس
I guess it's not in the ocean. I think he said it was a lake.
أعتقد أنّه ليس في المحيط، قال أنها بحيرة
A fishing spot not in the ocean?
موقع صيد ليس في المحيط؟
Here we go! Another bite! What a haul!
!ها هي! أمسكت بواحدة أخرى !يا للصيد الوفير
Ok!
!هيّا
No Trespassing
ممنوع الدخول
Shinobu-san left?
غادرت شينوبو-سان؟
She was in a bad mood. Happens all the time; no biggie.
كانت في مزاج سيّئ، هذا شائع الحدوث فلا تقلقي
You sure that wasn't your fault? What a weirdo.
ألم تكن أنت السبب؟ ما أغربك
A huge haul!
!صيد وفير
Whoa! Awesome!
!مذهل
Way to go, Dad!
مُبهر يا أبي
Where's that fishing spot?
أين كان موقع الصيد ذاك؟
I wanna fish too!
!أريد الصيد أيضاً
No, I can't tell you.
لا، لا يمكنني إخباركم
Why not?
لمَ؟
It's a secret spot my fishing friends told me about!
إنّه مكان سرّي أخبرني عنه !زملائي في الصيد
He's no fun...
هذا ليس مسليّاً
Let's go play beachball!
!لنلعب كرة طائرة الشاطئ
Yeah!
!أجل
Over there!
!هناك
Yay!
!مرحى
Conan-kun! Come on!
!كونان-كن! تعال معنا
No thanks...
...حسناً
Huh?
ماذا؟
Isn't that a parrot fish?
أليست هذه سمكة ببغائية؟
What about it?
وما في ذلك؟
No, nothing!
!لا شيء
How do you catch an ocean fish in a non-ocean fishing spot?
كيف تصطاد سمكة محيط في موقع صيد خارج المحيط؟
He probably bought 'em somewhere.
لعلّه اشتراها من مكان ما
Mori Kogoro! He's not just a great detective!
موري كوغورو! مواهبه الغزيرة !لا تتوقف عند التحرّي فحسب
Mori Kogoro?
موري كوغورو؟
Oh? Who were you again?
ماذا؟ من أنت؟
My bad!
إنّها غلطتي
What's this?
ما هذا؟
There's paper inside...
توجد ورقة
What could be written on it?!
ما المكتوب بها يا ترى؟
What if it's a treasure map?!
ماذا لو كانت خريطة كنز؟
This is like out of a movie or novel!
!كأنّه فيلم أو رواية
We got it!
!خرجت
What the...
...هـ-هذه
"SOS Shinobu?!"
رسالة استغاثة، شينوبو"؟"
Don't tell me...
...أ-أيمكن
...Shinobu-san needs help-
...شينوبو-سان تحتاج المساعدة
and sent that message?!
وأرسلت تلك الرسالة؟
She's up to that again? I thought she left.
ظننتها غادرت، لكن ها هي تفعل هذا مُجدداً
Again?
مُجدداً؟
Yeah. She does it all the time. Lemme see.
أجل، تفعل هذا كثيراً. أروني
She's trying to worry me. She can be a real nuisance.
تحاول جعلي أقلق عليها، يا لإزعاجها أحياناً
You can say that again...
يا للإزعاج حقّاً
It's almost full tide. Maybe I should go again...
سيرتفع المدّ قريباً، ربما عليّ الذهاب مرّة أخرى
Guys! Don't go into the ocean, it's dangerous!
!يا رفاق! لا تذهبوا للمحيط، سيكون خطيراً
Okay!
!حاضر
But things are bad if Shinobu-san really did send an SOS!
لكن ستكون مشكلةً كبيرة إذا أرسلت شينوبو-سان طلب استغاثة حقّاً
We'll have to check for ourselves!
علينا التحقّق من الأمر بأنفسنا
But where do we start?
لكن أين نبدأ؟
If she's on a desert island, we'll never--
...إذا كانت على جزيرة مهجورة، فلن نستطيع
No, that's impossible time-wise! Plus the paper's not dried up!
.كلا، ذلك مستحيل من ناحية الوقت كما أنّ الورقة لم تجفّ بعد
She's not very far away!
لم ترسلها من مكان بعيد
Hey, Ran-neechan.
!ران-نيتشان
Don't let Kasuda-san out of your sight.
لا تتركي كاسودا-سان يغيب عن ناظريك أبداً
But why?
لمَ؟
We're counting on you!
!نعتمد عليك
Wait! Where are you guys going?!
!لحظة! أين تذهبون؟
Alright! I'll give another crack at it!
!حسناً! سأصطاد مُجدداً
Great! I'll come with you, Mori-san!
!سأرافقك يا موري-سان
I know about your fishing spot; we're expanding into this area.
،أعرف موقع الصيد الذي تذهب له فشركتنا تتوسع في هذه المنطقة
Well, let's go!
!لنذهب
Dad! We need to start packing up!
!أبي! علينا البدء بتوضيب أغراضنا
Ugh! You're all so selfish!
!يا إلهي! جميعكم أنانيّون
People these days!
...الناس هذه الأيام
Excuse me, Mister!
!المعذرة يا جدّ
Not more?!
من جديد؟
Hey, you!
!أنتم
Lousy sea-bathers and divers!
!أيّ سباحة وغوص تقومون بهما؟
Excuse us...
...المعذرة
How dare they dirty my ocean!
!كيف تجرؤون على توسيخ محيطنا؟
Excuse us!
!المعذرة
What?
ما الأمر؟
Do you know where that bottle floated in from?
أتعرف من أين جُرفت هذه القنّينة؟
This?
هذه؟
This way, guys!
!من هنا يا رفاق
Right!
!نعم
Genta-kun.
غينتا-كن
What's that for? We're not here to gather shellfish!
لمَ معك هذه؟ لم نأت لصيد المحّار
Aw, shaddup! I can't just come here and not catch anything!
اصمت! لا يمكنني الرجوع دون صيد !المحّار والأنقليس بعدما أتيت للمحيط
You're always thinking about food!
!كلّ ما يشغلك هو الطعام يا غينتا-كن
Let's get some top shells too!
!لنجمع نهيد بحر أيضاً
Now you're here just to catch stuff...
لا تريدون إلّا الصيد الآن جميعاً
You ok, Ayumi?!
أأنتِ بخير يا أيومي؟
I think so...
نوعاً ما
It's almost full tide! Be careful!
ذروة المدّ قريبة، توخّي الحذر
Look!
!انظروا
Shinobu-san?!
شينوبو-سان؟
It has to be!
لا بدّ أنّها هي
Hurry! The cave's filling up with water!
!بسرعة! الماء يدخل الكهف
Shinobu-san! Are you all right?!
شينوبو-سان! أأنتِ بخير؟
Stay with us!
!تماسكي
Shinobu-san!
!شينوبو-سان
Whew!
!حمداً لله
It's you!
إنّهم أنتم
What happened?!
ماذا حصل؟
What happened, Shinobu-san?
ما حلّ بك يا شينوبو-سان؟
A cave that disappears into the ocean at high tide...
كهف يختفي بماء المحيط عند ذروة المدّ
But when I drank the juice he brought...
...لكن بعدما شربتُ العصير الذي جلبه
...I suddenly got sleepy.
غلبني النعاس فجأةً
There were probably sleeping drugs in the juice.
كان هناك مُنوّم داخل العصير غالباً
He wanted his murder to look like an accident!
أراد قتلك وجعل الأمر يبدو حادثة
He'd create an alibi while you drowned here.
يصنع حجّة غياب بينما تغرقين هنا
His nearly hitting us and starting that fight with you
اصطدامه الوشيك بنا، وتعرّفه علينا وافتعاله الشجار معك
was all part of his plan!
كان كلّه جزءاً من خطّته
But why?!
لكن لمَ؟
That's for the police to find out. Let's get out and contact them!
ذلك عمل الشرطة، لنخرج من هنا ونتّصل بهم
Conan-kun! Look!
!كونان-كن! انظر
The tide's coming in!
!المدّ يدخل
No way!
!مُحال
Let's get out of here!
!لنرجع بسرعة
Out of the boat! The tide's rising!
!اخرجوا من القارب! المدّ يرتفع
Hurry!
!بسرعة
Oh no!
لا-لا يُعقل
Now how do we get back?!
كيف سنرجع الآن؟
The waves are too high for us to swim out!
!الموجات عالية جدّاً فلا نستطيع الخروج سباحةً
Plus Shinobu-san isn't fully back to normal!
كما أنّ شينوبو-سان لم تستعد وعيها تماماً
Oh no!
!كلا
Someone help!
!النجدة
I don't wanna die!
!لا أريد الموت
Everyone calm down! Don't panic!
!اهدؤوا جميعاً، لا تهلعوا
That's easy for you to say!
!يسهل عليك قول هذا
If the water fills up to our heads...
...إذا ملأ الماء الكهف
...we'll all drown!
!سنغرق جميعاً
What do we do now?!
ما العمل؟ ما العمل الآن؟
What's that?!
...ذلك
What is that?
ما هذه؟
A firefly!
!يراعة
Fireflies?
يراعات؟
Here?
في مكان كهذا؟
That is strange!
هذا غريب بالفعل
What're they doing in a cave that fills up with water twice a day?!
ماذا تفعل في كهف يمتلئ بأسره بالماء مرّتين يومياً؟
Could it be?!
...أيمكن
Could what be?!
أيمكن؟
Maybe the cave has another exit that they came in from?!
!ربما للكهف مخرج آخر، ودخلت منه
What?!
!مـ-ماذا؟
Another exit?!
!مخرج آخر؟
It's our only way out now!
!هذا مهربنا الوحيد الآن
But what if it's too small for people?!
لكن ماذا لو كان لا يتّسع للبشر؟
Oh no!
!لا يمكن
Hey, Conan! We're not fireflies!
!لسنا يراعات يا كونان
The old man's parrot fish was big but had no scars!
السمكة الببغائية التي اصطادها العمّ كانت كبيرة لكن بلا أيّ ندبات
It's not that small of an exit!
!ليس مخرجاً صغيراً
It entered the cave during the high tide before dawn!
دخلت الكهف أثناء ذروة المدّ قبل الفجر
It probably got washed through the cave and into that lake
جُرفت داخله ووصلت للبحيرة ...حيث كان العمّ
the old man was at!
!يصطاد غالباً
A non-ocean fishing spot where you can catch ocean fish!
موقع صيد تصطاد فيه أسماك المحيط !رغم أنّه ليس محيطاً
That makes sense!
!فهمت
That's our Conan-kun!
!كما يُتوقع من كونان-كن
Sorry, old man! Guess you didn't buy 'em after all!
آسف يا عمّ، يبدو أنّك لم تشترها فعلاً
We'll drown if we stay here!
!سنغرق إذا بقينا هنا
I have faith in Conan-kun!
!أنا أثق بكونان-كن
Alright! Let's go!
!حسنٌ، لنذهب
What is it, Ayumi-chan?!
!ما الخطب يا أيومي-تشان؟
Water dripped from the ceiling...
تساقط ماء من السقف
Whew...
هـ-هذا إذاً؟
Don't scare us like that!
!لا تخيفينا
Sorry!
آسفة
It's like a maze...
إنّها أشبه بالمتاهة
Which way leads out?
من أين نخرج؟
The wrong way will get us lost...
إذا سلكنا الطريق الخطأ سنتوه وحسب
But the tide will catch up if we don't hurry!
!لكن إذا لم نسرع، سيصلنا ماء المد
Alright! Let's just go this way!
!حسناً، لنذهب من هنا بأيّ حال
Wait, Genta!
!انتظر يا غينتا
Huh? What the... It's a dead end!
ماذا؟ ما هذا؟ طريق مسدود
I told you!
!أخبرتك
Take the path with fireflies!
سنسلك الطريق الذي تأخذه اليراعات
Good thinking!
!تفكير سليم
They'll lead us to the exit!
!سيقودنا للمخرج بلا شكّ
Split up and look for 'em!
!لننفصل ونبحث عن اليراعات
OK!
!حسناً
I'll help too! I'm all better now!
سأساعد بدوري! فقد تحسّن حالي
None here!
!ليست هنا
Nor here!
!ولا هنا
Same here!
ولا هنا
I found them! They're here!
!وجدتها! إنّها هنا
Alright! Let's move out!
!حسناً! لننطلق
Left or right? It's one or the other...
يميناً أم يساراً؟ إمّا نسلك أحدهما أو الآخر
Alright! Look for more fireflies!
!حسناً، لنبحث عن اليراعات مُجدداً
No luck. Both are empty.
لا جدوى، الاثنان فارغان
I guess this is the end...
وصلنا النهاية أخيراً
Don't say that!
!لا تقل ذلك
What do we do, Conan-kun?!
ما العمل يا كونان-كن؟
There's still a chance.
لا تزال هناك طريقة
This way!
!من هنا
Ah! You listened for the different echoes!
!فهمت! استمعت لاختلاف الصدى
Yeah!
أجل
The louder echo was a dead-end. The quieter one leads ahead!
،الصدى المرتفع كان طريقاً مسدوداً بينما المنخفض يؤدي لطريق
You're amazing, Conan-kun!
!مُذهل يا كونان-كن
Ok! Let's go!
!حسناً، هيّا بنا
Push!
!ادفعني
Harder!
!اسحبوا أقوى
What's that sound?!
مـ-ماذا؟ ما هذا الصوت؟
Birds!
!طيور
Birds?!
طيور؟
They probably came in looking for food!
!دخلت تبحث عن طعام وما شابه غالباً
They're flying toward the exit!
!إنّها تتّجه نحو المخرج
Alright! Follow them!
!حسنٌ، لنلحق بها
Are you all right?!
أأنت بخير؟
Endure it! Let's run!
!تحمّل! لنواصل الركض
Come on, guys! Hurry!
!هيّا يا رفاق، بسرعة
I'm fine!
!أنا بخير
I can't hear them anymore!
لم أعد أستطيع سماعها
Don't tell me...
...أيمكن
...they're already outside?
خرجت بالفعل؟
Yeah. We were too late.
أجل، تأخّرنا
Stupid birds scaring me!
طـ-طيور؟ أخافتني
What's the matter?
ما-ما الخطب؟
Just wondering if the peak tide was in...
كنتُ أتساءل ما إن وصل المدّ ذروته بالفعل
Where did they run off to?!
يا إلهي، أين ذهبوا؟
Ran-neechan.
ران-نيتشان
Don't let Kasuda-san out of your sight.
لا تتركي كاسودا-سان يغيب عن ناظريك
Whoops!
!كلا
Be sure to take your trash when you leave!
لا تنسي أخذ قمامتكم عند مغادرتكم
Mister! Do you know the best fishing spot around here?!
يا جدّ! أتعرف أين أفضل موقع صيد في هذه المنطقة؟
Which way now, Conan?!
أين نذهب الآن يا كونان؟
Which is it?!
أيّهم؟
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
I don't know.
لا أدري
What?!
!لا يمكن
It's the tide!
!إنّه المدّ
Help!
!الـ-النجدة
Grab on to me, Shinobu-san!
!تمسّكي بي يا شينوبو-سان
Someone!
!النجدة
Help!
!أنقذوني
Darn it! Are we stuck in a dead end?!
تبّاً! أدخلنا طريقاً بنهاية مسدودة؟
The light!
!المصباح
It's pitch dark!
!الظلام حالك
What is this?!
!ما هذا؟
Now I see! We were at the top of the cave!
!فهمت! كنّا في أعلى الكهف
The water's flowing through to the other exit now!
!الماء يجري نحو المخرج الآخر الآن
Where are we?!
!أين نحن؟
I can't tell what's up or down, left or right!
لا أستطيع تمييز اليمين من اليسار !ولا الأعلى من الأسفل هكذا
Where will we--
...أين نحن
That's the exit!
!إنّه المخرج
Here it comes!
!ها هي
What happened?
ماذا حصل؟
I'm stuck!
!أنا عالق
Darn it! It's too narrow for him!
!تبّاً! الفتحة ضيقة على غينتا
His life jacket! If I can just get it off!
...سترة نجاته! إذا استطعتُ خلعها
It's no use! I'll have to tear it!
...لا جدوى! عليّ تمزيقها
It won't rip! Isn't there anything I can use?!
!تبّاً، لا تتمزق! أليس هناك ما يمكنني استعماله؟
His rake!
!هذه أداة صيده
Ok! Take this!
!حسناً! خذ
I'm out of breath!
!لا أستطيع كتم نفسي أكثر
I thought we were goners!
!ظننتني سأموت
We're alive!
!نجونا
What're you doing here?!
!ما-ما هذا؟ لمَ أنتم هنا؟
Yep! I was right!
!كما ظننت تماماً
The water from the high tide flows into the lake!
!الماء من ذروة المدّ يصبّ في هذه البحيرة
The lake's water doesn't rise because it doesn't flow just one way;
سبب عدم ارتفاع منسوب مائها هو أنّه لا يجري من اتّجاه واحد فحسب
it also flows out during low tide via another passageway!
!بل يخرج أثناء تدنّي الجزر عبر مخرج آخر سفليّ
But it's narrow, so less water flows in during high tide!
لكنّ ذاك المخرج ضيّق، فتقلّ كميّة الماء الداخلة أثناء ذروة المدّ
How'd you get here anyway?!
!كيف وصلتم هنا؟
I figured this might happen! Good thing I came just in case!
توقّعتُ حدوث هذا، من الجيّد أنّي جلبت هذا معي تحسّباً
What?!
!ماذا؟
Ayumi!
!أيومي
Ayumi-chan!
!أيومي-تشان
Don't move!
!لا تتحركوا
Teruhiko-san! Stop this!
!تيروهيكو-سان! توقّف
Just what are you--
...ما الذي
Shut up!
!اخرس
Mister! Use that and your fake-accident plan will be in vain!
أوني-سان، إذا استعملت هذا فلن يكون هناك معنى لخطّة الحادثة المزيّفة التي ابتكرتها
You think I won't shoot, kid? I have enough bullets for you all!
تظنّني لن أطلق يا فتى؟ لديّ رصاصات تكفي لكم جميعاً
Stop it!
!توقّف
Stop it, Teruhiko-san! It's me you want to kill!
توقّف يا تيروهيكو-سان! أنا من تريد قتلها، صحيح؟
She has nothing to do with this!
!لا علاقة لهذه الطفلة
Yeah, it's your fault! You have to die!
!أجل، إنّها غلطتك! عليك الموت
Why? Why are you doing this?!
!لمَ؟ لمَ تفعل هذا؟
My old man ordered me to marry some monkey-girl!
أمرني أبي أن أتزوّج فتاةً أشبه بالقرد مثلك
I have no intention to leave home and be poor with you!
لا نيّة لديّ بترك المنزل والعيش فقيراً معك
I want to stay a rich kid!
!أريد البقاء شاباً ثرياً للأبد
You're terrible!
!فـ-فظيع
What a bastard!
!يا للحقير
But all I have is a rake!
!لكن كلّ ما لديّ هي أداة صيد
I don't have my Power Shoes or any other weapons!
!حذاء تقوية الركل وبقيّة أسلحتي ليست معي
Could this really be the end?!
أهذه النهاية هذه المرّة حقّاً؟
I can't leave you alive now that you know the truth.
لا يمكنني ترككم أحياء بعدما عرفتم الحقيقة
I'll turn you all into fish food!
سأجعلكم جميعاً طعاماً للسمك
Imbecile! The sign says no trespassing!
!أحمق! ممنوعٌ دخول هذا المكان
You'll pay for hurting girls!
!ستدفع ثمن أذية الفتيات
A huge victory for the Junior Detective League!
!نصر كبير لفرقة فتيان التحرّي
It was an incident full of thrills, suspense, adventure,
كانت حادثةً مليئة بالإثارة والتشويق والمغامرة
and a little bitterness.
وبعض المرارة
Imbecile! I'll take those!
!أحمق! سأخذ هذه معي
Those are my--
...إنّها
You still don't get it?!
!لا تزال لا تفهم؟
He was fishing in a restricted area that's dangerous at high tide.
كان يصطاد في منطقة محظورة خطرة بسبب ذروة المدّ
Shinigami Jinnai!
!شينيغامي جينّاي
Give yourself up!
!سلّم نفسك
The culprit's still on the 7th floor! I just saw his shadow!
!لا يزال المجرم في الطابق السابع يا عمّ !رأيتُ ظلّه للتو
Why did he shoot?!
لمَ أطلق النار؟
And where in the building did he hide to avoid police detection?!
وأين اختبأ في هذا المبنى متوارياً عن أنظار الشرطة؟
The Shinigami Jinnai Murder Case
جريمة قتل ملك الموت جينّاي
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Elevator.
مصعد
Next episode a mysterious killer appears.
!ظهور قاتل غامض في الحلقة القادمة
I am the mysterious killer.
أنا القاتل الغامض
No, I am the mysterious killer.
بل أنا القاتلة الغامضة
No, it is I.
!بل أنا